Win or lose... Everyone has their fight.
Never Back Down is a drama, action film directed by Jeff Wadlow.
Jake, full of anger after his father's death, is just starting to find a place for himself at his new Orlando high
school - until Ryan, head of an underground MMA fight club, picks Jake out as a prime opponent.
After being trounced by Ryan in front of the entire school, Jake begins training under
the firm, moral guidance of a MMA master, where he learns how to fight...
and how to avoid a fight.
But it becomes obvious that a rematch will be inevitable if Jake
wants to stop Ryan and his bullying, once and for all.
Jake Tyler, played by Sean Faris.
Baja Miller, played by Amber Heard.
Ryan McCarthy, played by Cam Gigandet.
Jean Roqua, played by Djimon Hounsou.
Max Cooperman, played by Evan Peters.
Margot Tyler, played by Leslie Hope.
Never Back Down is a 2008 American martial arts sports drama film directed
by Jeff Wadlow and starring Sean Faris and Cam Gigandet.
It tells the story of a frustrated and conflicted teenager who arrives at a
new high school and discovers an underground fight club there.
The film was theatrically released on March 14, 2008 by Summit Entertainment.
It received generally negative reviews from critics, though it successfully
grossed $41.6 million worldwide against a budget of $20 million.
It was followed by a titular film series, which included three sequels.
The film explores themes of high school, martial
arts, sports, fight, underground.
The tone is emotional.